# Suraj Poddar

8051212333 surajpoddar16@gmail.com Amit Marble, Upper Bazar, Ranchi - 834001

http://www.surajpoddar.com http://suraj-poddar.herokuapp.com/

### **Profile**

I am a multi-disciplinary web/mobile designer and developer from Ranchi. I have worked with startups and consultancies over the years.

I specialize in designing and developing responsive websites, native and hybrid mobile apps with focus on appearance, accessibility and performance.

## Experience

#### **DEVELOPER/ PARTNER, HEAPTREE, PATNA – 2016-PRESENT**

Currently working as a partner at Heaptree, a remote software consultancy firm. I am responsible for managing, designing and developing web and mobile based applications. Over an year I have designed and developed products for multinational companies like TATA, Lafarge, Nestle, JSW Cement and consulted startups like Highwaydelite.

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER, TASKBOB, MUMBAI - 2015-2016

As a full stack developer at Taskbob my main role was to develop browser based tools for Taskbob. Was responsible for the iterative development of Taskbob website, order fulfillment dashboard and servicemen onboarding dashboard.

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER, JUGNOO - 2015**

As a full stack developer at Jugnoo I developed and maintained Jugnoo Meals and Jugnoo Fatafat server APIs.

#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN, JUGNOO - 2014 -2015

Worked as an intern at Jugnoo in the product development division. I was responsible for development of Jugnoo Meals app server APIs along with development of order fulfillment and on boarding web applications.

### Education

2015: B.E, Electronics and Communication engineering, BIT Mesra - 70.2%

2011: Class 12th, International Public School, Ranchi - CBSE: 77% - AIEEE: 6841

2011: Class 10th, Oxford Public School, Ranchi - CBSE: 92%

## Skills

SDK: Android, Ionic

Frameworks: AngularJs, ExpressJs, Jquery, Bootstrap, ThreeJs

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, Java, HTML, CSS, C/C++

DBMS and ORM: MySQL, Sequelize

Design: Sketch, Photoshop

VCS: Git

## **Personal Projects**

**CLUB BITMESRA – 2017** 

Co-created the Slack Community for BIT Mesra with over 800 members and counting.

**ONLINE CHESS – 2015** 

Developed a multiplayer online chess game using ThreeJs, NodeJs and Socket.IO

**BRAILER - 2015** 

Developed a prototype typing tool for blind people, with a simple 6 key swipe keyboard

BITOTSAV, PANTHEON WEBSITE - 2013 - 2014

Designed and developed web application for technical and cultural fests of BIT Mesra

### Extra Curricular Activities

**TECHNICAL COORDINATOR, IEEE BIT MESRA** 

Co-created the Slack Community for BIT Mesra with over 800 members and counting.

MEMBER OF ORGANISING COMMITTEE, BITOTSAV BIT MESRA

Was responsible for developing and managing Bitotsav (cultural fest) web portal

**HOBBIES** 

In my spare time I like to travel and take photographs. I am a regular swimmer and Call of Duty addict.